Contact

mmajardim@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/manuel-jardim-249243 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Retail

Banking

Accounting

Languages

English (Full Professional)

French (Limited Working)

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

Manuel Jardim

Entrepreneur

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Summary

Entrepreneur adding value to different businesses. Open to interesting and profitable investments.

I have gathered significative experience as a General Manager and as a CFO, working in these positions for 12 years. For the last eight years I have been working as the General Manager of CMS Rui Pena & Arnaut, Law & Tax Firm.

Just before, I played an operational and strategic role, managing the start up "Palavras e Atitudes", in the business of global hygiene services.

Until October 2010, I worked at INAPA (Paper Distribution) for two years and a half, as the Marketing Director.

I had acquired further expertise in retail during 4 years, while I worked with the CEO of the Papelaria Fernandes Group in the business of Stationery Distribution and Retail. My work consisted mainly in managing the Group's retail chain with the Managing Director.

In the first decade of my career I worked in retail as the CFO of Marks & Spencer for 6 years (reporting to London and Madrid), and in banking before that.

Experience

Diversos

Entrepreneur

October 2019 - Present (6 months)

Lisboa

Activo em investimento e assessoria de start ups

CMS Rui Pena & Arnaut

General Manager

February 2012 - September 2019 (7 years 8 months)

Lisbon

Business and overall Management of CMS Rui Pena & Arnaut, a leader in Law & Tax services providing, operating in Lisbon, and since 2012 a member of CMS, which has 70 offices across the globe, located in 39 different Countries.

Palavras e Atitudes

Owner

2010 - October 2012 (2 years)

Service Provider of Global Hygiene Solutions for Companies, in Partnership with a big player.

Inapa Portugal
Marketing Director
June 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 5 months)

Marketing Director of the Portuguese Branch of the INAPA Group

Papelaria Fernandes Group Director Adjunto da Administração 2004 - 2008 (4 years)

Operations Director, managed the chain of stores working with the Managing Director and the board of directors.

Marks & Spencer (Portugal), Lda CFO

February 2000 - May 2002 (2 years 4 months)

I was the CFO for the subsidiary of M & S in Portugal. Reporting to the Board in Spain and the UK, I was responsible for the accounting, treasury, planning, controlling, store procedures, contacts with lawyers, auditors, banks and suppliers. I was the most senior person in Lisbon's management team.

CRB - Marks & Spencer Franchise in Portugal CFO 1996 - 1999 (3 years)

BNU Economist/Dealer 1992 - 1996 (4 years)

Education

University of Cambridge

MBA, Generalist · (2002 - 2003)

Nova School of Business and Economics Gestão das Sociedades de Advogados, Law firms management · (2014 - 2014)

Fundação Getulio Vargas

Planeamento Estratégico em Sociedades de Advogados, Law firms management · (2013 - 2013)

Universidade Católica Portuguesa Licenciatura, Economics · (1985 - 2001)